paulinaontheroad.com 2019-10-06

# Privacy Policy - Paulina on the road...

Skip to content

Privacy Policy[Paulina](https://paulinaontheroad.com/author/paulinawp2/ "Posts by Paulina")2019-09-02T11:35:51+02:00

## Affiliate links:

Note that “Paulina on the Road” has financial relationships with some of the merchants mentioned on this blog. “Paulina on the Road” may be compensated if consumers choose to utilize the links located throughout the content on this site and generate sales for the said merchant. You are not obligated to click on any link or buy any products that are advertised.

“Paulina on the Road” is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to [Amazon.com](https://amazon.com/). As an Amazon Associate, I earn from qualifying purchases. “Paulina on the Road” is also a participant with the Booking.com Affiliate Program.

How do we travel? Unless otherwise noted, we pay for our own trips and expenses.

## GDPR compliance:

* We promise that we take data safety seriously and we use your private data only to offer a personalized experience.  
* We use Mailchimp for our newsletter, which you can opt out of, and Google Analytics for analyzing website data.  
* If you subscribed to our newsletter, you will receive our newsletters. You can always unsubscribe by following the link in email or by emailing us.  
* If you gave us your name, it will only be used to personalize the newsletters  
* We have never sold, we are not selling, and we will not sell any of your personal data provided to us  
* All of our affiliates are GDPR compliant  
* You have the right to:  
– be informed regarding how the data is collected and used  
– have access to the data about you  
– ask us to change the data about you  
– ask us to delete the data about you  
– ask us to stop sending your newsletters

“Paulina on the Road” abides by GDPR regulations, so if you wish to have your information (e.g. comments removed) and you’re an EU resident, please get in touch with us. I am happy to amend/remove your information/comments/email from the mailing list if you contact me. We do not retain secondary copies of commenters/reader contact information without permission. Similarly, we do not resell or share your contact information with third parties. Similarly, once you opt out of the mailing list, you are permanently removed.

## What information is collected:

Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website: We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form.

Automatically-Collected Information: We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked. Your information has been anonymized and only is viewed aggregately.

Cookies: We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

## HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED

To operate and maintain the Website;  
To send you newsletters. Each email promotion will provide an easy opt-out button;  
To respond to your comments or inquiries;  
To track and measure statistics/advertising on the Website;  
To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

## THIRD-PARTY USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information. Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

This Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:  
Google Analytics – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics. We have anonymized our Google Analytics data and never look at non-aggregated data.

MailChimp – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications. Please refer to Mail Chimp’s privacy policy for further information.

## COOKIES

We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

## **ADVERTISING**

“Paulina on the road” is a member of the Mediavine Advertising Network, which serves content and advertisements while you visit the Website, which may use cookies, as noted above.

## SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION

If you leave a comment, certain information (your name as you provide it) may be publicly visible, however your email address will not be. We will not contact you using your email as this goes against GDPR regulations, so if you wish to be contacted by “Paulina on the Road”, please contact us directly. Please do not request that we contact you in the comments.

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

## CHILDREN’S INFORMATION

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately. We will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

## Google Analytics Addendum

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files saved on your computer, to help the website analyze how you use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. If this website anonymizes IP addresses, your IP address will be truncated by Google within a EU member state or other EEA state before being transmitted to the US. Only in exceptional situations will your full IP address be transmitted to Google servers in the United States and truncated there. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. You can also prevent Google from collecting information (including your IP address) via cookies and processing this information by downloading this browser plugin and installing it: [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

You can prevent data collection via Google Analytics by clicking here. An “Opt-out Cookie” shall then be applied to your website which shall prevent any future collection of your data when visiting this website.

Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at the [Google Analytics Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) or at the [Google Analytics Privacy Overview](https://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html). Please note that on this website, Google Analytics is supplemented by “gat._anonymizeIp();” to ensure anonymized collection of IP addresses (IP masking).

## reCAPTCHA

We use the reCAPTCHA service provided by Google Inc. (Google) to protect your submissions via internet submission forms on this site. This plugin checks if you are a person in order to prevent certain website functions from being (ab)used by spam bots (particularly comments). This plugin query includes the sending of the IP address and possibly other data required by Google for the Google reCAPTCHA service. For this purpose your input will be communicated to and used by Google. However, your IP address is previously truncated by Google within member states of the European Union or in other states which are party to the agreement on the European Economic Area and is, as such, anonymized. Only in exceptional cases is a full IP address transmitted to a Google server in the United States and truncated there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of this service. The IP address provided by reCaptcha from your browser shall not be merged with any other data from Google.

This data collection is subject to the data protection regulations of Google (Google Inc.). For more information about Google’s privacy policy, please visit: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

By using the reCAPTCHA service, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

## CONTACT INFORMATION

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, [please get in touch](https://paulinaontheroad.com/contact/).

Privacy Policy updated September 2nd, 2019.
